

Software OA Tester albertjacobg@gmail.com +639271309402

Portfolio: https://dev-albertjacobg.netlify.app/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-gonzales-6487a1249/

# **SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE**

Experienced Software QA Tester supporting the Philippines' leading provider of financial services specializing web and mobile applications. With strong analytical skills, attention to detail and problemsolving abilities. Effective communication skills honed through previous contact center experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Knowledge in Python, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git
- Knowledge in web development tools such as React and Tailwind
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Test Cases & Processes
- Functional Requirements
- Regression and Negative Testing
- Web and Mobile Testing
- Defect/Bug Tracking Jira and RTC Defect Management Tool
- Backend Testing, API Testing, Mainframe Testing (SQL Developer, SoapUI)
- Knowledge in Automation Testing (Java Selenium, TestNG)
- Customer Service Skills
- Software and Hardware Troubleshooting
- Ticketing and Documentation
- Active Directory

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Nityo Infotech, Inc. - Contracted with Bank of the Philippine Islands (BPI)

March 2023 – Present

Position: Software Quality Assurance Tester Project: BPI Web and Mobile Application

Duties and Responsibilities:

- 1. Executing UAT test cases.
- 2. Performing functional testing, backend testing and downtime testing.
- 3. Bug reporting and management.
- 4. Collaborating with development team to resolve defects.



## Atos Information Technology Inc.

May 2022 – October 2022 (6 months)

Position: IT Service Desk Analyst

Project: Gas and Electricity account (US and UK)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- 1. Troubleshoots through inbound calls of hardware and software problems (third party and inhouse applications) involving technical resources to ensure resolution;
- 2. Supports O365, Cisco AnyConnect, GlobalProtect, Zscaler issues and access requests.
- 3. Password reset and account unlock using active directory.
- 4. Ticket handling of issues and requests using ServiceNow.
- 5. Provides occasional functional and technical guidance to less experienced staff;

#### IBM Business Services, Inc.

March 2021 – April 2022 (1 year and 1 month)

Position: HR Contact Center Representative

Project: Healthcare account (US) Duties and Responsibilities:

- 1. Receive inbound and outbound calls from employees and answer HR inquiries such as HR policies, payroll, benefits and recruitment.
- 2. Guiding and educating employees using HR management tool (Workday) and timekeeping tool (Kronos).
- 3. Document all calls with regards to the caller's inquiries accurately using ServiceNow.
- 4. Provide password reset and account unlock to recruitment site, Taleo.

#### Alsons/AWS Information Systems, Inc. - Contracted with Accenture, Inc.

April 2019 – June 2020 (1 year and 2 months)

Position: Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Projects: Healthcare account (Singapore), Grocery chain account (Spain)

**Duties and Responsibilities:** 

- 1. Analyzing and reading of requirements.
- 2. Test case writing and execution.
- 3. Write and track bug reports using Jira/RTC.
- 4. Work in coordination with the development team to resolve issues and complete the project activities.
- 5. Provide or assist in training to newly hired Software QA.

### **EDUCATION**

2014-2017 AMA Computer College

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science